<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <metadata>
        <source>
            <title>Kew Gardens</title>
            <author>Virginia Woolf</author>
            <illustrator>Vanessa Bell</illustrator>
            <publisher>Hogarth Press</publisher>
            <pubDate>1927</pubDate>
            <format>Book</format>
            <archive>British Library</archive>
        </source>
        <edition>
            <editor>avr</editor>
            <consultant>ebb</consultant>
            <place>Penn State Behrend</place>
            <date>2021</date>
            <license>Public Domain</license>
        </edition>
    </metadata>

    <book>
        <page n="1"> KEW GARDENS BY VIRGINIA WOOLF DECORATIONS BY VANESSA BELL THE HOGARTH PRESS </page>
        <page n="2"> Kew Gardens by Virginia Woolf decorated by Vanessa Bell published by the
            Hogarth Press </page>
        <page n="3"> This edition, published in 1927, is limited to 500 numbered copies, of which
            this is number 150 </page>
        <page n="4"> From the oval-shaped flower-bed there rose perhaps a hundred stalks spreading
            into heart-shaped or tongue-shaped leaves half way up and unfurling at the tip red or
            blue or yellow petals marked with spots of colour raised upon the surface; and from the
            red, blue or yellow gloom of the throat emerged a straight bar, rough with gold dust and
            slightly clubbed at the end. </page>
        <page n="5"> The petals were voluminous enough to be stirred by the summer breeze, and when
            they moved, the red, blue and yellow lights passed one over the other, staining an inch
            of the brown earth beneath with a spot of the most intricate colour. The light fell
            either upon the smooth, grey back of a pebble, or, the shell of a snail with its brown,
            circular veins, or falling into a raindrop, it expanded with such intensity of red, blue
            and yellow the thin walls of water that one expected them to burst and disappear.
            Instead, the drop was left in a second silver grey once more, and the light now settled
            upon the flesh of a leaf, revealing the branching thread of fibre beneath the surface,
            and again it moved on and spread its illumination in the vast green spaces beneath the
            dome of the heart-shaped and tongue-shaped leaves. </page>
        <page n="6"> Then the breeze stirred rather more briskly overhead and the colour was flashed
            into the air above, into the eyes of the men and women who walk in Kew Gardens in July.
            The figures of these men and women straggled past the flower-bed with a curiously
            irregular movement not unlike that of the white and blue butterflies who crossed the
            turf in zig-zag flights from bed to bed. The man was about six inches in front of the
            woman, strolling carelessly, while she bore on with greater purpose, only turning her
            head now and then to see that the children were not too far behind. The man kept this
            distance in front of the woman purposely, though perhaps unconsciously, for he wished to
            go on with his thoughts. </page>
        <page n="7" facs="../docs/img/page7.jpg">
            <description resp=""/>
            <line n="1">"Fifteen years ago I came here with</line>
            <line n="2">Lily," he thought. "We sat somewhere over</line>
            <line n="3">there by a lake and I begged her to marry me</line>
            <line n="4">all through the hot afternoon. How the dragon-</line>
            <line n="5">fly kept circling round us: how clearly I see</line>
            <line n="6">the dragon-fly and her shoe with the square</line>
            <line n="7">silver buckle at the toe. All the time I spoke</line>
            <line n="8">I saw her shoe and when it moved impatiently</line>
            <line n="9">I knew without looking up what she was going</line>
            <line n="10">to say: the whole of her seemed to be in her shoe.</line>
            <line n="11">And my love, my desire, were in the dragonfly;</line>
            <line n="12">for some reason I thought that if it settled</line>
            <line n="13">there, on that leaf, the broad one with the</line>
            <line n="14">red flower in the middle of it, if the</line>
            <line n="15">dragon-fly settled on the leaf she would</line>
            <line n="16">say "Yes" at once.</line>
        </page>

        <page n="8" facs="../docs/img/page8.jpg">
            <description resp=""/>
            <line n="1">But the dragon-fly went round and round: it</line>
            <line n="2">never settled anywhere—of course not, happily</line>
            <line n="3">not, or I shouldn't be walking here with Eleanor</line>
            <line n="4">and the children—Tell me, Eleanor. D'you</line>
            <line n="5">ever think of the past?"</line>
            <line n="6">"Why do you ask, Simon?"</line>
            <line n="7">"Because I've been thinking of the past.</line>
            <line n="8">I've been thinking of Lily, the woman I might</line>
            <line n="9">have married.... Well, why are you silent? Do</line>
            <line n="10">you mind my thinking of the past?"</line>
            <line n="11">"Why should I mind, Simon? Doesn't one always</line>
            <line n="12">think of the past, in a garden with men and</line>
            <line n="13">women lying under the trees? Aren't they one's</line>
            <line n="14">past, all that remains of it, those men and women,</line>
            <line n="15">those ghosts lying under the trees,... one's happiness,</line>
            <line n="16">one's reality?"</line>
            <line n="17">"For me, a square silver shoe buckle and a</line>
            <line n="18">dragon-fly—"</line>
        </page>

        <page n="9" facs="../docs/img/page9.jpg">
            <description resp=""/>
            <line n="1">"For me, a kiss. Imagine six little girls sitting</line>
            <line n="2">before their easels twenty years ago, down by</line>
            <line n="3">the side of a lake, painting the water-lilies,</line>
            <line n="4">the first red water-lilies I'd ever seen. And</line>
            <line n="5">suddenly a kiss, there on the back of my</line>
            <line n="6">neck. And my hand shook all the after-</line>
            <line n="7">noon so that I couldn't paint. I took out</line>
            <line n="8">my watch and marked the hour when I</line>
            <line n="9">would allow myself to think of the kiss</line>
            <line n="10">for five minutes only—it was so precious—</line>
            <line n="11">the kiss of an old grey-haired woman with</line>
            <line n="12">a wart on her nose, the mother of all my</line>
            <line n="13">kisses all my life. Come, Caroline, come,</line>
            <line n="14">Hubert.</line>
            <line n="15">"They walked on past the flower-bed, now</line>
            <line n="16">walking four abreast, and soon diminished in</line>
            <line n="17">size among the trees and looked half trans-</line>
            <line n="18">parent as the sunlight and shade swam over their</line>
            <line n="19">backs in large trembling irregular patches.</line>
        </page>
    </book>
</xml>
