<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <source>
        <title>Kew Gardens</title>
        <author>Virginia Woolf</author>
        <illustrator>Vanessa Bell</illustrator>
        <publisher>Hogarth Press</publisher>
        <pubYear>1927</pubYear>
    </source>

    <book>
        <page n="7">
            <border
                img="https://www.bl.uk/britishlibrary/~/media/bl/global/dl%2020th%20century/20th%20century%20collection%20items/kew-gardens-by-virginia-f60161-76.jpg">
                <text> "Fifteen years ago I came here with Lily," he thought. "We sat somewhere over
                    there by a lake and I begged her to marry me all through the hot afternoon. How
                    the dragonfly kept circling round us: how clearly I see the dragonfly and her
                    shoe with the square silver buckle at the toe. All the time I spoke I saw her
                    shoe and when it moved impatiently I knew without looking up what she was going
                    to say: the whole of her seemed to be in her shoe. And my love, my desire, were
                    in the dragonfly; for some reason I thought that if it settled there, on that
                    leaf, the broad one with the red flower in the middle of it, if the dragonfly
                    settled on the leaf she would say "Yes" at once. </text>
            </border>
        </page>

        <page n="8">
            <border
                img="https://www.bl.uk/britishlibrary/~/media/bl/global/dl%2020th%20century/20th%20century%20collection%20items/kew-gardens-by-virginia-f60161-77.jpg">
                <text> But the dragonfly went round and round: it never settled anywhere—of course
                    not, happily not, or I shouldn't be walking here with Eleanor and the
                    children—Tell me, Eleanor. D'you ever think of the past?" <dialogue>"Why do you
                        ask, Simon?"</dialogue><dialogue>"Because I've been thinking of the past.
                        I've been thinking of Lily, the woman I might have married.... Well, why are
                        you silent? Do you mind my thinking of the past?"</dialogue><dialogue>"Why
                        should I mind, Simon? Doesn't one always think of the past, in a garden with
                        men and women lying under the trees? Aren't they one's past, all that
                        remains of it, those men and women, those ghosts lying under the trees, ...
                        one's happiness, one's reality?"</dialogue>
                    <dialogue>"For me, a square silver shoe buckle and a
                    dragonfly—"</dialogue></text>
            </border>
        </page>

        <page n="9">
            <border
                img="https://www.bl.uk/britishlibrary/~/media/bl/global/dl%2020th%20century/20th%20century%20collection%20items/kew-gardens-by-virginia-f60161-78.jpg">
                <text>
                    <dialogue>"For me, a kiss. Imagine six little girls sitting before their easels
                        twenty years ago, down by the side of a lake, painting the water-lilies, the
                        first red water-lilies I'd ever seen. And suddenly a kiss, there on the back
                        of my neck. And my hand shook all the afternoon so that I couldn't paint. I
                        took out my watch and marked the hour when I would allow myself to think of
                        the kiss for five minutes only—it was so precious—the kiss of an old
                        grey-haired woman with a wart on her nose, the mother of all my kisses all
                        my life. Come, Caroline, come, Hubert."</dialogue> They walked on past the
                    flower-bed, now walking four abreast, and soon diminished in size among the
                    trees and looked half transparent as the sunlight and shade swam over their
                    backs in large trembling irregular patches. </text>
            </border>
        </page>
    </book>
</xml>
